Guide to the Myron Golden Photograph Collection 1950's PR 303
New-York Historical Society
Myron Golden Photograph Collection
1950's
New-York Historical Society
PR 303
0.83 Linear feet (1 box)
This collection consists of approximately 100 photographs and negatives depicting buildings and people in New York City in the 1950's.
Arrangement
These materials are arranged by subject.
Provenance
Gift of John Conrad Weiser, 2009
Access Restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of approximately 50 gelatin silver prints depicting people and buildings in New York City in the 1950's. The collection also includes some of the negatives for these prints, as well as additional negatives for which there is no print. Subjects include chess players, kids, businesses, an outdoor art show, the Polo Grounds, fishing on the piers, billboards, and other New York City scenes. Also included are a few photographs that were apparently taken outside of New York City.
Streets -- New York (State) -- New York.; New York (N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc. -- Photographs.; New York (N.Y.) -- Photographs.; Gelatin silver prints.; negatives (photographs)
- Series I: Gelatin silver prints
  - Street scenes, kids (includes kid playing stickball) (4), 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - Street scenes, adults (includes chess games in Washington Square, woman on roller skates, card players, woman with camera and man shoveling snow) (6), 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - Street scenes, buildings (Bedford Street, MacDougal Street, Patchen Place, Cherry Lane Theater, views from 302 West 12th Street) (8), 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Street scenes, buildings (unidentified) (3), 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Street scenes, dismantled elevated subway (2), 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Street scenes, businesses (funeral parlor on Jane Street, Third Avenue antique importers) (5), 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hudson river piers (includes people fishing) (6), 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - Outdoor art show (12), 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - Broadway billboards at night (2), 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - Men painting billboard for State Senate election next to "Buy U.S. Savings Bond" poster, 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - E.J. Sperry Thought Factory (Chicago?), 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cigar store Indian, 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - Self-portrait, Myron Golden, 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
- Series II: Negatives
  - Horses in van, 1953 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - New Faces [Broadway show](2), 1953 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Building and empty lot (2), 1953 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Institute of Design, 1953 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chess players, Washington Square (2), 1954 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hudson River from 302 West 12th Street, 1954 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Gansevoort dock (2), 1954 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hudson River dock (fishing), 1954 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Washington Square, 1954 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - 67 West 3rd Street, 1954 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Leroy Street, 1954 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - 302 West 12th Street, 1954 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Polo grounds (6), 1954 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - 3rd Avenue windows (2), 1955 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cradle-Mass Productions (2), 1955 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Subway (4), 1955 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Jane Street, 1956 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Negatives of printed images, 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)